<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>
<channel>
	<title>Aman Dhakad</title>
	<atom:link href="https://amandhakad.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://amandhakad.com/</link>
	<description>Exploring physics, tech, and truth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 20:12:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.9</generator>
<image>
	<url>https://amandhakad.com/site_assets/uploads/2021/05/cropped-image-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Aman Dhakad</title>
	<link>https://amandhakad.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Hacking the universe &#8211; A manifesto</title>
		<link>https://amandhakad.com/hacking-the-universe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aman Dhakad]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 02:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Default]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.amandhakad.com/?page_id=57</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[<p>Understanding the Infinite. My life is devoted to &#8220;Knowing everything&#8221;. Needless to say, to know everything, it&#8217;s not necessary to know each and every useless fact that can exist. We can just know and understand the most fundamental truths behind everything, over which all knowledge and understanding can be built. Therefore in better terms, the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amandhakad.com/hacking-the-universe/">Hacking the universe &#8211; A manifesto</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amandhakad.com/">Aman Dhakad</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h3>Understanding the Infinite.</h3>
<p>My life is devoted to &#8220;Knowing everything&#8221;. Needless to say, to know everything, it&#8217;s not necessary to know each and every useless fact that can exist. We can just know and understand the most fundamental truths behind everything, over which all knowledge and understanding can be built.</p>
<p>Therefore in better terms, the aim is to know all the necessary truths that govern this universe (physics and our reality), the necessary truths beyond this universe (multiverse/god/creator/supreme reality) and the possible mechanism of these truths (truths behind these truths).</p>
<p>Knowing everything is possible. It&#8217;s just difficult.</p>
<h3>Hacking the universe.</h3>
<p>Elon Musk wants to make human life multiplanetary, and he is focusing on the rockets. Is it the only solution? From Physics eyes, Rocket&#8217;s are too classical and we are at the edge of our physics. If we only knew everything about the universe, there might be laws in fundamental physics, which can completely change the way we can travel across the universe.</p>
<p>Hacking the universe only means, finding such laws or exploits that will allow us to solve biggest problems of mankind, <strong>from death to ruling the galaxies.</strong></p>
<p>Physics provides a good framework to approach the hacking. However, it might not be enough to actually hack it.</p>
<h4>Approaches</h4>
<p><strong>Based on Physics</strong></p>
<p><em>&#8220;The universe do as the Physics dictates.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Either of these 3 scenarios is possible:</p>
<ol><li>The laws of physics allow the universe to be hacked.</li><li>The laws of physics do not allow the universe to be hacked, but exploits can be found. (Physics can be broken)</li><li>The universe does not contain any exploits and so, it is impossible to hack the universe.</li></ol>
<p>To verify if scenario 1 is true, we must complete fundamental physics. The ultimate puzzle to be cracked in Physics is the grand unified <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theory_of_everything" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Theory of Everything.</a></p>
<p>If we happen to be in scenario 2, then we must go beyond Physics. We will require technological superpowers to help us find these exploits that break physics.</p>
<p><strong>Singularity is inevitable!</strong></p>
<p>Technology is not limited. For it contains many superpowers, a really fascinating one, is Intelligence. Human Intelligence was good, but there could be more to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_general_intelligence" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">intelligence</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_general_intelligence" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AGI</a> in past was mainly limited by hardware limitations. Thanks to Moore&#8217;s law, the hardware won&#8217;t be the limitation very soon. Now, building AGI is just a software problem, which can eventually be solved by human creativity.</p>
<p><strong>Mathematical Universe</strong></p>
<p>I have been studying Mathematics, can anyone show some link between the problems of our mathematics and the problems of our universe? I have seen a paper by Max Tegmark, in which, he pushes the idea of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_universe_hypothesis">universe being mathematical structure itself</a>.</p>
<p>For this universe is mathematical, a deeper understanding of pure mathematics might reveal significant secrets of nature.</p>
<p><strong>God is helpful!</strong></p>
<p>Remember, Exploits are not intended part of universe, so the scenario 2 suggests the idea of Intelligent Creator who neglected these exploits when creating the universe. If there is an intelligent creator, we must attract his attention. This is somewhat of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simulation_hypothesis" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">simulation hypothesis</a> + Religious approach.</p>
<p>Scenario 3? The only way to verify scenario 3, is to falsify 1 &amp; 2. We are very far from falsifying them, and so we must not look at 3 yet.</p>
<h3>What&#8217;s stopping us?</h3>
<p>This is a story that i am telling myself. In the history, we have achieved wonderful things, with narratives like we as a civilization is actually going somewhere. We had dreams of the future. And we achieved them.</p>
<p>However, the culture is shifting, and humans are becoming more entangled with things that do not really exist in nature. Where exactly are we going? Why are we secretly becoming nihilists?</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t have concrete solutions but i think we should find better stories to tell ourselves. Because there is an actual game to play. The game is nature itself. The game is universe itself. We can <a href="https://www.amandhakad.com/win/">win</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amandhakad.com/blog/">Read the blog &#8212;&gt;</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amandhakad.com/hacking-the-universe/">Hacking the universe &#8211; A manifesto</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amandhakad.com/">Aman Dhakad</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Free will died a long time ago.&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://amandhakad.com/free-will-died-a-long-time-ago/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aman Dhakad]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 22:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Physics Archive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Truth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amandhakad.com/?p=732</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[<p>There are some truths, that are fundamental, that are non-negotiable. Words have difficulties explaining them. But they can be understood. All you need is sincere observation, and sincere questioning. One of them is this. You don&#8217;t do anything. Nobody does anything. Things just happen. Why do you think you do anything? Who is it that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amandhakad.com/free-will-died-a-long-time-ago/">&#8220;Free will died a long time ago.&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amandhakad.com/">Aman Dhakad</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p>There are some truths, that are fundamental, that are non-negotiable. Words have difficulties explaining them. But they can be understood. All you need is sincere observation, and sincere questioning.</p>



<p>One of them is this.</p>



<p><strong>You don&#8217;t do anything. Nobody does anything. Things just happen.</strong></p>



<p>Why do you think you do anything? Who is it that does these things? Is there a choice, when things happen?</p>



<p>Understand this, there is no choice in existence. Things just happen. And you are not the doer. You cannot do anything.</p>



<p>Look inside you. Look at the decisions you make. Could you have decided anything else? Is it not the causes, that do the effects?</p>



<p>Web of events, this universe is. A million things in history causing one small thing now. One small thing now contributing to million things happening in future. But no one did anything.</p>



<p>The reason you believe you are the doer is, because you think. Thoughts create your ego and ego feels like it is the doer.</p>



<p>But truth is truth, ego is not the doer. No one is the doer. </p>



<p><strong>No one is there to do anything.</strong></p>



<p>Ego is false, you are false.</p>



<p>&#8220;<em>Free will died a long time ago.</em>&#8220;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>Additional notes to people who see this through the lens of physics:</p>



<p><strong>Beware physicists.</strong></p>



<p>If you look at physics, this was the philosophy of it. The universe had no choice.</p>



<p>But then came, Quantum Mechanics, and people lost their minds. Things started seeming to be non-deterministic.</p>



<p>Does this suddenly, enables choice? A free will of the universe?</p>



<p>Well, no.</p>



<p>This is well explained by Max Tegmark in this <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/quant-ph/9709032.pdf" target="_blank">beautiful and simple paper</a>. But I&#8217;ll write a poor explanation in my words here:</p>



<p>An instrument, does not collapse the state of object in superposition. Since, the instrument is also quantum mechanical. It is also being observed by the object. It is in superposition as well. Both instrument and object in the superposition of states. Suddenly, the instrument records one state of object, just like object records one state of instrument recording that one state of object.</p>



<p>These two entities are just updating their own personal memory, but from outside perspective, there is no non-determinism that happened here. Both were in superposition of two states. That means both has separate existence, where they mutually update their memory based on their world.</p>



<p>Yes, I was talking about Many-Worlds Interpretation and no the universe does not suddenly split.  The universe exists as superposition of all states. We the individual entities just keep updating our memory.</p>



<p>Everett understood quantum mechanics. Max Tegmark understand quantum mechanics. And Einstein wasn&#8217;t wrong when he said:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>&#8220;God does not play dice with the universe.&#8221;</p><cite><em>Albert Einstein</em></cite></blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amandhakad.com/free-will-died-a-long-time-ago/">&#8220;Free will died a long time ago.&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amandhakad.com/">Aman Dhakad</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Win.</title>
		<link>https://amandhakad.com/win/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aman Dhakad]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 18:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.amandhakad.com/?p=372</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[<p>Win. A question to be asked &#8211; Win against who? Useless to win against other people. Useful to win over one&#8217;s own mind. But real winning lies, in fighting face-to-face with God. The creator. The only thing we know about creator, is his creation. The nature. It can be exploited. It can be hacked. Truth [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amandhakad.com/win/">Win.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amandhakad.com/">Aman Dhakad</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span id="more-372"></span>
<p>Win.</p>
<p>A question to be asked &#8211; <strong>Win against who?</strong></p>
<p>Useless to win <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_science" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">against other people.</a></p>
<p>Useful to win over one&#8217;s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moksha" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">own mind.</a></p>
<p>But real winning lies, in fighting face-to-face with God.</p>
<p><strong>The creator.</strong></p>
<p>The only thing we know about creator, is his creation.</p>
<p>The nature.</p>
<p>It can be exploited.</p>
<p>It can be <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ESXOAJRdcwQ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hacked.</a></p>
<p>Truth can be seen.</p>
<p>Immortality can be<strong> </strong><a href="https://balajis.com/the-purpose-of-technology/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">achieved.</a></p>
<p>God can be uncovered.</p>
<p><strong>Physics can be <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theory_of_everything" target="_blank">completed.</a></strong></p>
<p>Win over <strong>nature</strong>.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s what is needed.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m tired of being a nihilist. It&#8217;s pathetic, to waste time.</p>
<p>So, here&#8217;s the objective purpose.</p>
<p>For all you nihilists.</p>
<p><strong>Win.</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amandhakad.com/win/">Win.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amandhakad.com/">Aman Dhakad</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
