<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>
<channel>
	<title>The Truth &#8211; Aman Dhakad</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/the-truth/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Exploring physics, tech, and truth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 08:10:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>
<image>
	<url>/site_assets/uploads/2021/05/cropped-image-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>The Truth &#8211; Aman Dhakad</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Introduction to The truth</title>
		<link>/introduction-to-the-truth/</link>
					<comments>/introduction-to-the-truth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aman Dhakad]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 07:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Truth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=703</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to intro of the truth. The truth is going to be a long series of short texts, where we would not only question the roots of our reality and truth, but even try to penetrate them and find our way out of this weird universe. There was a serious need for this. We all [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/introduction-to-the-truth/">Introduction to The truth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Aman Dhakad</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Welcome to intro of the truth. <strong>The truth </strong>is going to be a long series of short texts, where we would not only question the roots of our reality and truth, but even try to penetrate them and find our way out of this weird universe.</p>
<p>There was a serious need for this. We all know the ultimate questions about our reality. We all ask, what&#8217;s the meaning of this universe, what&#8217;s existence, why does the physics work and if there&#8217;s anything behind the universe. Or even, who is god? Will we meet god? Is the universe a simulation? Are any of those ancient guys correct? Why do i think? Am i just atoms, or there&#8217;s something else? The questions are many, but all connected to each other.</p>
<p>What most don&#8217;t know is that it is actually possible to find the answers. It is actually possible to know the actual reality, which most would believe impossible. </p>
<p>The problem is, you won&#8217;t find the truth by reading one book, or exploring one subject, or doing one thing. Truth is everywhere. You will have to look at it from everywhere, from every subjects, from every viewpoint. </p>
<p>The questions will remain same, it&#8217;s just that we will turn every stone out there to find answers.</p>
<p>Another problem is, expressing truth. Once you finally arrive at a conclusion, once you get the feel about it, it&#8217;s so difficult to convey it to others. Because, they don&#8217;t see the same things that you have seen. Because, what you see is the connection of dots that you found one by one, deducing things and then connecting them.</p>
<p>This perfect combination of dots, cannot be expressed in words. It&#8217;s a vision. And visions are so difficult to express. You can&#8217;t share the same vision through words. You will have to show the things from all viewpoints. The seeker will automatically connect the dots, and the vision will build automatically. One day, the seeker will see the same thing as you see. But it takes time.</p>
<p><strong>Where to look?</strong></p>
<p>First, that the truth is not at the root of one subject. It&#8217;s not possible to say, that learn all physics and you would know it. I can&#8217;t say just meditate and you would know it. </p>
<p>Because, no you will not know it like that. And whatever i told you, you won&#8217;t know it unless you would ask the same questions yourself and find different ones. Questioning is the heart of exploration. The only thing changed in this series is, that we will leave no stone unturned to find the answers.</p>
<p>There are no opinions, there are no beliefs in this series. All we will do is Ask serious questions and question serious answers. The vision must build automatically.</p>
<p>End.</p>
<p><em>The first part of the truth will be uploaded in next few days.</em> <em>You should subscribe.</em></p>
<div id="mc_embed_signup">
<form action="https://amandhakad.us1.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=b5bcd302aeef4df11eb4d8d0c&amp;id=d4f1014313" method="post" id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" class="validate" target="_blank" novalidate="">
<div id="mc_embed_signup_scroll">
	<label for="mce-EMAIL"><p></p>
<h2 class="widget widget-title heading-size-3">Subscribe</h2>
<p><br>
	<input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" class="email" id="mce-EMAIL" placeholder="email address" required=""><br>
    </p>
<div style="position: absolute; left: -5000px;" aria-hidden="true"><input type="text" name="b_b5bcd302aeef4df11eb4d8d0c_d4f1014313" tabindex="-1" value=""></div>
<p></p>
<div class="clear"><input type="submit" value="Subscribe" name="subscribe" id="mc-embedded-subscribe" class="button" style="padding: 10px 20px;"></div>
<p></p></label></div>
</form>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/introduction-to-the-truth/">Introduction to The truth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Aman Dhakad</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/introduction-to-the-truth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
